I'm about to break down every single
Grockbot concept that you have to
understand in order to start getting
immediate value out of your Grockbots.
So, let's not waste any time and just
get straight into today's video. So, in
today's video, I've got 25 concepts for
you guys, and they're split across five
parts. So, part one is what the bot is.
So, a Grockbot is one single bot. As you
can see, I've got a bunch over here, and
each one has a name, a job title, and a
description. So, as you can see, if I
click on motion, which is actually
building the animations for this video
that you saw already, his name is
Motion. You can see right here, he's got
a tag that says animator. So, if I click
in, you can see that it says label. And
the description for this bot is that
this bot creates motion graphics and
animations for intros or transitions for
YouTube videos. And you can see that
each of my different bots I'm having one
very specific conversation with. So,
each bot is very much their own
individual bot with their own skills,
their own descriptions, their own
processes, and you have unique
conversations with them. And now, that's
a really nice segue into number two,
which is bot descriptions. Because you
can see here that you're going to start
to build out a ton of different bots.
You want to make sure that each one is
doing one very specific job very well.
So in this case, you saw Motion's
description. If I went to Miner and we
looked at his description, mine's X for
AI news, new models, and new tools. Also
knows Nate's YouTube and expost so the
briefings stay useful for his content.
If I go to this bot called eyes, I can
click in and see that this description
is that this bot is a master at
research. It gathers lots of credible
sources and helps form opinions based on
facts and data. Now, the reason why
these descriptions are so important is
because as we get into different
concepts later, you're going to notice
that these bots work together a lot. And
the way that they're able to understand,
I need to delegate work to eyes because
he's the researcher or I need to
delegate work to motion because he is
the animator is all based on those
descriptions. So, these descriptions are
super super important because what's
really cool about Grockbot is as you
build more and you scale them up, you
might think that you want to build some
sort of ecosystem like this where you're
up top talking to all your bots. But
really what you want to do is you want
to build more of an ecosystem like this
that looks more like an org chart where
you talk to just a few executives and
those executives know all of the bots
underneath and they know which ones are
on their teams and what their strengths
and weaknesses are. And that's kind of
where you can see what I've got going on
up here with my seuite, but we'll talk
more about that later. And that brings
us on to number three, which is bot
templates. So this is really cool. Do
you remember how in Nadend you could
bring in other people's end templates?
In cloud, you can bring in other
people's skills, things like that. Well,
in Grockbot, you can bring in other
people's Grockbots. So look at this link
for example. This is a Grockbot that I
called studio. It creates photos,
graphics, and short video creative for
marketing. So what I can do is I can
actually add this to my own Grockbot. It
opens it up in the app and I can read
through the context here. So
instructions, memories, skills, and then
I can just add this bot. And what
happens is it spins up this bot and then
it just basically starts creating
itself. Here you can see it says on it
I'm saving your memory and skill. Now if
I click into the bot you can see it
already has a name, a label and a
description. Of course you will have to
configure your own things. So if someone
gives you a bot that's connected to
their ClickUp it's not going to be
connected to their ClickUp. You would
have to connect it to yours but still it
basically has the other assets in there.
Just nothing personal. And the other
cool thing is you can share your own
bots. So let's say I wanted to share my
views bot. I could just come in here,
click on the settings, and right here,
click share as template. And this
basically says, "Hey, views, create a
template of yourself that I can give to
someone else." And there you go. Now,
Views has created its own link, which I
can go ahead and publish. And now, if
anyone copies this link, they'll be able
to pull in views and have that bot in
their own bot ecosystem. Look at this.
I'll copy the link. I'll go to Google,
paste that in. And now, anyone can go
ahead here and copy views. Which brings
us on to number four, which is kind of a
two-parter. Context and memory. Context
is basically all of the stuff that your
Grock bots have access to to see. So the
conversation history and anything else
that you're feeding in like your
prompts. And the second piece of that is
memory. And this is really interesting
because right here you can see that when
I asked views to make a template of
itself, it said, "Yeah, I'm just going
to read through my memories first." And
if I come into the details, we can see
here in the context that there are
specific memories that it actually
saved. And if someone copied this bot
template, they would also get those
memories. But what's really interesting
is the difference between all of your
Grockbot like global memory and
individual bot memory. So watch this.
Hey views, can you quickly tell me what
is the difference between what you know
about me from a global perspective that
all other Grockbots know and then what's
the memory stuff that only you know
about me? So the point I'm trying to
make here is you have all these
different bots and overall they have
like a collective file of information
about you. But as you converse with each
bot and you build up their capabilities,
they have different memories
individually too. Here you can see
there's two distinct memory stores. This
is what every bot is able to see about
me and this is what only views knows
about me. So make sure you are
understanding what agents know what. And
if you want to update the memory just
say hey add this to your memory or add
this to the global memory. And now that
brings us on to concept number five
which is compaction. So if you guys have
used something like cloud code before
then you're probably aware of the whole
idea of like filling up the context
window and being careful to make sure
you're not entering into context rot
territory. Now, with Grockbot, it's a
little bit different because each
individual agent has their own
conversation history, which means they
have their own context windows. But the
thing about Grockbot is it autocompacts
everything. So, we don't get to control
that. We also don't know exactly when it
autocompacts, but it has some sort of
like auto summarization and compacting
capability so that it doesn't hit that
context window. So, if I've been talking
to views for like 500 days, it probably
wouldn't see my first couple messages,
but overall, it would have memories kept
about me, and it would have context of
what we're trying to work towards, and
it would see, you know, maybe the last
30 or maybe the last 50 messages as a
summary while it's taking action. All
right, so those are the first five. Now,
we're moving into part two, which is
where it works. All right, cool. So,
number six is the agent computer. Now,
what this means is that your Grockbots
can actually use a computer. As you can
see, Claus has a computer right here,
and I can look at his screen, and he can
also control his screen. If I go over
here to Becky, you can see that she's
also got a computer open as well. Every
single one of your Grockbots has a
computer. Now, this is kind of similar
to memory because they all kind of have
their individual screens that they're
working on, but at the end of the day,
they're all working on the same
computer, and you'll understand that a
bit better when we move into concept
number eight. But moving on to concept
number seven is the idea of a browser.
So, inside of the computer, obviously, I
can open this up and I can drive this
browser or Claus can because that's the
bot right here. But what happens in the
browser is we can literally just use
Google the same way we might want to if
we were actually on our own Google
Chrome or whatever it may be. And what's
cool about that is it saves your login.
So, I logged into school. As you can
see, this is my account. And if I close
out of this, it's going to stay logged
in. So, now Clouse is able to actually
do things inside of my school community
for me. Or it could log into my GitHub
or it could log into my LinkedIn. It can
log into things pretty much once. We
save the credentials. So you would
basically just come into the site you
want. You would log in. You would enter
your own username and password. And then
your bot could just take control and do
stuff in there for you. And now moving
on to number eight, we have the file
explorer. So just like on my screen, you
can see right here, I've got a local
file explorer. I can look through my
Herk 2 project. I can look through my
camera roll. I can look through all of
that kind of stuff. So can all of your
agents. And this is where they share all
of this stuff. If I open up our actual
workspace, you can see that I've got
stuff like brainstorms. I've got
dashboards. I've got Grockbot Concepts,
which is the video that you're watching
right now. And all of these files that
are being looked at are the exact same
ones on every computer for the bots. So,
if I go over here to let's just go to
dev and I'll open up this screen, you
can see that if we open up the file
explorer on Dev's computer, it's the
exact same workspace with all of the
same files that are stored across the
shared computer for your Grockbots. And
while we're still on this whole concept
of the computer, moving on to number
nine is the terminal. So, just like you
have a terminal on your computer, so do
these bots. They can run commands. They
can set up scripts. They can do things
through a terminal just like this as
well. So it's literally just a computer.
They can do everything that a computer
can do. And then moving on to number 10,
we have local file access. So that means
that yes, they have a cloud computer
that they all share. But whatever
computer that you're actually working
on, they can access local files. So
right here you can see that I gave it a
file path which was in my downloads. I
said analyze this file and tell me
what's in it. It grabbed it. It analyzed
it. I told it to rename it and then move
it. And it actually was able to rename
it and move it. So, if I go into my new
thumbs, this is the file that it was
talking about right here. It used to be
in my downloads and it was just called
like, you know, orange blah blah blah.
And then it looked at it, it renamed it
to zero to pro and then it moved it
inside of this new thumbs folder and it
did this locally on my own desktop. All
right, so those are the first 10. Now,
let's move on to part three where we are
going to talk about its abilities. Okay,
so concept number 11 here is called
plugins. This is basically how you let
your agents actually talk to things like
your Slack or your Gmail or your Google
Docs, whatever it may be. And you go
down here to the plugins and you can see
that there are a bunch of options to
choose from and pretty much all you have
to do is click add and then you just
sign in. It couldn't be easier. And
what's also cool is you can see the ones
that you're already authenticated into
and you can connect multiple accounts.
So let's say for ClickUp, I like to have
my main account as well as a different
account. So I can authenticate into both
of them and then have different agents
use different accounts. So, right here
in my ClickUp, you can see that it's
actually creating tasks for everything
that it's doing. Here is when it started
working on the motion graphics for this
video. And my Grockbots know that they
need to be logging their tasks inside of
this board in ClickUp, so I can always
see what's going on. So, once again,
this is the one for this video. And you
can see that we have an owner, we have
what I asked, we have the deliverable,
we have links, we have all of this
information and progress updates. And
this is really good for me to just be
able to keep tabs on what's going on
and, you know, look back at the week and
see everything that they did. And moving
on to number 12, this is skills. So,
just the same way that you use skills in
Claude or Codeex, you can do a slash
command and then you could reference
some sort of skill. So, if I come in
here and I type school, you can see that
this one says like 7-day challenge posts
on school. And that is a skill that I
could actually invoke and the agent
understands how to use it. And if you've
never heard of a skill before, real
quick, it's basically just a recipe. So,
let's say you wanted to make chocolate
chip pancakes. Well, you'd probably pull
up a chocolate chip pancake recipe, then
you'd make the pancakes, and then you'd
realize, okay, cool. These were really,
really good. I want to make them really,
really good every time. So, I'm just
going to save this recipe. So next time
I want to make chocolate chip pancakes,
I just read the recipe and hey, if these
weren't good, if they were too raw or
they were too burnt, why don't I just
update the recipe and say, "Hey, next
time cook these a little longer on each
side or cook them less." So these skills
are editable and every time you run
them, they can get better because you
just give feedback. You find the skills
inside of your plugins. You go to the
installed and then you look at these
private plugins and these are all of
your skills that your Grockbots can use.
So you can see I have like an AIS Plus
recording post. I have Grill Me. I have
Fireflies Inest. These are basically
just processes that your agents will
probably do more than just once. Then
you turn it into a skill. And a good
skill has things like when to use it,
the exact order of operations, and
anything that if it could go wrong, what
you do. And speaking of skills, let's
move on to number 13, which is teach a
task. Whenever you're somewhere in the
browser, I typically think that you do
this on Chrome, but whenever you're in
here, you can click on this button that
says teach a task. And remember that
skill that you guys saw earlier, the
like 7-day challenge post and AIS Plus?
This was a teach a task where I
basically came into here. I clicked on
record. Now you can see the screen's
being recorded. It says Klaus is
watching and learning. So then I could,
you know, click into this tab. I could
go to news and then I could go ahead and
like open up this link. And then when I
go ahead and stop recording, Klaus gets
that message. It watches that
demonstration and it turns what you just
did into a skill. So this is going to be
some skill called like find Chicago Cubs
food news and whatever. But the point
being you can either create skills with
natural language and instructing what a
process looks like or you can basically
have them shadow you. You could record
for a couple minutes, pull some reports,
analyze some data, whatever you need to
do, and then it will automatically turn
that into a skill for you. As you can
see, it decided to save that skill as a
search Google News. Now, obviously,
that's a pretty useless skill, but just
trying to demonstrate the point here.
Now, moving on to number 14, we have
routines. You can see that right here, I
have one called Sunday work log archive,
which runs every Sunday at 8 p.m. And in
order to create one, you can basically
just say, "Hey, can you do this for me
every day at 5:00 p.m.?" Or you could
just click on this plus and then set one
up. Right here you can see I'm setting
one up called AIS 7-day challenge likes.
And what I'm doing is I'm telling it to
run a skill. So routines make something
happen automatically. And that thing
that happens automatically can be a
skill. So I chose interval and I decided
to let this one run every single minute.
So I'll just sit here and let this
trigger. So you guys can see how that
looks. So it's been a minute. You can
see that this routine's firing. We can
see that Claus is working down here. So
it found the skill file. It's reading
it. And now it's going to be able to
take action using that skill. And you
can see in the browser, it just opened
up a new tab. I'll make this full
screen. And you guys can just watch it
actually take action here and start
liking those posts. So, at the top of
the screen, you can see that it searched
for the word challenge. It just clicked
into a post and now it's scrolling down
and it's going to click on the like
button. Boom. There we go. Okay, while
that skill is finishing up, I'm going to
move on to number 15, which is web
hooks. Now, I know web hooks sounds like
a technical word, but it's really not.
Just think of it like someone ringing on
your doorbell. Because in the routine
section, you can see that they can be
triggered based off a time like a
schedule, every hour, 5:00 pm, or it can
be off of an event. So these are event
triggered routines like someone ringing
your doorbell. That could be on a Slack
message, on a team message, or a web
hook. And these are all basically the
same thing. This one is just like you
can configure your own web hook call. So
let me show you an example. I've got
this bot down here called web hook. And
I created it just for this
demonstration. If I go into this app
that I created, what happens is I fill
in this information. So I will just put
Nate. I will put Natek88gmail.com
and I will put hello I need a new dog.
And when I send this request, what this
does is it actually sends a web hook. So
it basically just shot a payload to this
web hook address. And you can see now
this bot has woken up. It's going to
take that payload. So basically the
information I submitted in that form and
it's going to take action for me. So you
could have agents automatically wake up
when you get a new email or a new Slack
message or a form submission or so many
other possibilities, a new CRM record
even. So what happened is it said, "Hey,
a form just came in asking for a new
dog. I emailed them that we got it and
we're processing it and I DM'd you in
ClickUp." So if I go to ClickUp, you can
see that I got a message from UpAI. If I
can make this a little bigger, you can
see that form just came in. And in my
email, you can see that we just got a
message which says, "We got your form
and you wrote, "Hello, I needed a dog.
We'll follow up soon." So obviously just
a quick demonstration, but the point
being you can have Grockbots take action
when something happens in your business
or in your life. Okay, so that was 15.
Now let's move on to part four, which is
how bots work together. This where it
gets like really cool. Okay, so the
first one is group chats. Now look at
this. I have a group chat with my
leadership team. I've got Klaus, Dan,
Chandler, Becky, and I could add members
if I wanted to or I could remove them.
And in here, I basically said, "Hey, I
need you guys to like tell me about our
long-term goals and ideulate on how
we're going to keep growing and scaling
the business." And because these are
different agents, my chief of staff,
COO, CFO, CCO, they're able to talk
about their own areas of expertise and
all the individual agents that they're
actually managing. Remember, I like to
use sort of like this vertical hierarchy
and they're able to all hear each other,
mention each other, and just ideulate.
And then I can come back and take a look
at what they've done. And that brings us
on to number 17 really perfectly, which
is mentions. You can see that Klaus
mentioned Becky right here. You can see
that Dan mentioned Becky and Klouse
right here. And if I click on that, it
actually takes me to that conversation.
So, you can actually see too that Claus
just finished that skill. And I'm going
to go ahead and disable that routine
because I don't want that to actually
fire every single minute. But what else
you can do is you can have agents
delegate workout by mentioning people.
So like, hey, could you please check
with and then I could just go in here
and mention, you know, like at Becky to
do X, Y, and Z. But the cool thing is if
your descriptions are good enough, you
don't actually have to explicitly
mention these bots. Klouse or whoever
you're talking to will be smart enough
to know that it should be delegating
work, but you can still message them in
chats just like that. And that brings us
to number 18, which is about handoffs.
Like I said, agents delegating work to
other agents. If I go to Becky right
here, you can see that I asked her to do
some stuff for creating um these motion
graphics that you're looking at, and she
delegated all this work to Motion. You
can see right here. Now, in here, if I
click into motion, we can see that the
actual conversation between them. So,
Becky said, "Hey, Nate needs this.
Here's what you need to do. Here are the
deliverables." And then they have a
conversation. And it can also be more
than just one agent. Right here, Klaus
was able to delegate work to coffee and
minor. And then down here, it also shot
off messages to minor and Becky. The
whole point is agents can work together
and you can also view their conversation
so you get full visibility into what
they're actually doing and talking
about. Which brings us on to number 19,
which is about replies. Say you're
talking to Klouse and there's a bunch of
things going on. A routine just fired,
you were building a skill, whatever. You
can use this little reply button to
actually isolate that conversation sort
of. So, if I click on this and say,
"Okay, very cool. Go ahead and run that
as a test." nice. And then I can also
respond to this, for example, and say,
"Very nice. Well done. You're crushing
it." And just like the way you reply to
things when you're actually in like
Slack or ClickUp, it's just able to
understand what you're responding to.
And the context is a little bit better
because if I randomly just said, "Okay,
cool. Go ahead and run that as a test,"
it might think that I wanted it to do
this again. Which I in fact do not.
Okay, so we've been through 19 concepts.
We've got six more to go. Moving on to
part five. We have how you control and
monitor it. So the first one is about
approvals. If you go in here to your
settings, you can see that we have
computer and this shows execution on
this computer. Let Grockbot open files
and run tasks on your computer. So this
is my actual local environment. Remember
we talked about the difference between
local files and the sort of like agent
computer in the cloud. Now sometimes
when you're talking to these agents,
they're going to ask you, they're going
to pause the workflow and say, "Hey, am
I allowed to do this?" And you can
either choose like always allow or allow
once. And you can change your default
setting over here as well. Which brings
us into concept number 21, which is
human takeover. Sometimes it's going to
hit a blocker where you're really the
only one that can take over. For
example, if you're asking it to do
something in LinkedIn, and it says,
"Okay, I've pulled up LinkedIn in my
browser, but you need to sign in." It
will pause and it will wait for human
takeover. This is usually when you need
to do something sensitive like put in
passwords or any sort of information
like that because what you don't want to
do is put passwords into the
conversation history right here because
technically that's going to SpaceX. I'm
not saying that anything really really
bad would happen, but if you do
accidentally send an API key or
password, then maybe just go ahead and
rotate it. And moving on to number 22,
we have weekly usage. So right here,
when you sign up for Grockbot, you get
on some sort of subscription, whether
it's like 20 bucks a month or 100 or
200, whatever it is, you can see weekly
usage. And this resets every 7 days. So
if this goes to 100 within your 7 days,
then you can't use this anymore unless
you want to pay extra for ondemand spend
or API billing. And you can just click
on this button if you want to change
your limit, increase it, decrease it, or
add some on demand credits. So, as
you're dealing with different bots and
as you're sending off prompts and you're
making different channels, just watch
this number because having things like a
group chat of agents is going to consume
more of your weekly usage than just
talking to one agent. And moving on to
number 23, we have run history. This
basically just means the ability for you
to check how many times routines have
been run. So, for example, with web
hook, this one is a eventbased one. So,
in the run history, we can see that we
had one 10 minutes ago and we also had
one at 5:48 p.m. Or if you have
something that's actually time based,
you could just click in to verify that
they are in fact running every Sunday at
the time that they should be. Or if this
one, you know, every minute, this would
have tons more history. Now,
unfortunately, you can't click into
them. You can just see that things ran,
but if they failed, there'd be an X
here. Hopefully, in the future though,
we're able to actually click into the
runs and see where they actually
happened in case we need to investigate
what went wrong. I do kind of have a fix
for that though, so just stay tuned.
Now, moving on to number 24, we've got
notifications. Now, this one's pretty
self-explanatory. It'll notify you if it
has a blocker or if something finishes
up. But you can also control
notifications per agent. So, what I like
to do is just have notifications on for
my main four, and you can come in here
and you can just enable notifications
when the bot finishes or needs input.
Now, what's really cool about that is
that you can also have the notifications
come to your phone, which is what I
like. You can see right here we've got
my phone, and it's perfectly synced with
my desktop. So, if I open up Klouse and
on my phone, I just say hello, as soon
as I send this, it pops open on my
desktop as well. So, even if my
computer's turned off, these both stay
perfectly synced. And getting the
notifications on your phone is awesome
because while you're at lunch, you're on
a walk, you can keep driving what you
need to drive from your pocket. And
finally, the last one we have is number
25, which is basically just about
managing your bots. Just the idea that
you can right click on them and you can
pin them, which moves them up here to
the top. You can also move them to a
different section. So, if I unpin this
one and then I go to move to, I could
move it to a new folder called whatever
I want, or I could move it to the
general or unassigned, or I could put it
into wherever I want really. And this
allows you to just fold them up and keep
things organized if you choose. Now, you
can also hide bots. So, for example, I'm
going to delete web hook, but if I don't
want to delete him, I could just hide
from sidebar. And that just puts them in
a section down here called hidden bots.
So, these aren't lost, but they're just
hidden. So, you can keep things clean.
You also have the ability to delete
them. You have the ability to share them
as a template. You can edit their
profile, you can mark them as unread,
and you can also duplicate them, which
is interesting because it basically just
spins up the exact same bot, but it
clears all the conversation history. So,
let's say for some reason you're getting
sick of how Claus is behaving, and maybe
you're like, uh, I just need to restart,
but I don't want to lose all the skills
and all the routines and everything. I
just want to like clear the conversation
history. The way you would do that is
you would just make a duplicate copy of
Klouse and then maybe just delete the
old one. And then the last one here is
just to copy the conversation ID. This
is really just more for if you need like
support and you want to send, you know,
Grock your conversation ID so it can
look into what happened. And that was
all 25. The last one I have real quick
for you guys that you kind of already
saw a little teaser about was number 26,
agent logging. Just the idea that
everything that these agents are doing,
you want to store them somewhere.
Whether that's a Google sheet, whether
that's a ClickUp like I've got, whether
that's a local Excel file or a SQL
database, whatever it is, store
everything your agents do. meaning tell
them whenever you are creating a new
project log the updates there updates
progress move it to complete archive it
things like that and then what you can
do is say hey at the end of every single
routine you're also going to log this
run and now you can have different
databases or different sections to just
see every single thing that your agents
are doing and I think that's really
important when you're using something
like Grockbot where it's so easy to make
autonomous agents and it's so easy to
just scale up a team you don't want to
lose visibility and you don't want to
lose control so please set up some form
of agent logging but anyways Guys, that
is going to do it for today. If you want
to keep diving in to more stuff with
Grockbot, then check out this free
2-hour course that I just dropped. Go
ahead. I'll see you guys over there.